hello
today's it come how does this work wait
can I go on YouTube level let's see go
go on our Twitter Oh God take that
painting down though that's true but
let's we saw 14 people maybe linked it
to discord all the channels yeah
YouTube lives would have a discord it's
a channel and I think why is Andy
dressed up why not be dressed up you
guys
tell us how good this quality is cuz for
me it looks fantastic oh happy I know I
have you both know I gotta figure out a
little more had fantastic quality thank
you
oh yeah no no no yeah I was acqua hired
by Apple so we know yeah details have
not been money and that's why you gotta
make money and that's what well you're
gonna know they're cost increase for
hardware let's get the time like a
couple of people have let's just oh we
have a hundred a lot of people ok few
minutes yeah all right guys I'm gonna
roll this dice and we got a 17 the good
news is we're not increasing the price
so yeah we you know what's the good news
is today the 17th no oh why well
nothing then we could have played a
little you know it's the 17th that we
rolled the 1700 not sponsored yet but
all right ok let's get started with nine
people watching
Oh someone was trying to sleep and they
got added all right sure yeah
you off comma connect on Android and iOS
just called complex comma connect to the
App Store yeah comma connect you know
they make the font size smaller you know
we might drop the connect at some point
but yeah this is gonna work so I can
like click on my Honda Civic here it's
not black and white in real life by the
way oh yeah it's a color oh my gosh I
keep my phone in black and white so it's
less addictive
don't be so Silicon Valley George but um
yeah you can like see where your car
drove it's gonna load up the video here
this was just me driving around the
block last week in my Civic why don't he
goes take a long time to learn this one
works Kinect is using start with that
yeah we could do more announcements all
later um so guys if you want to go right
now
- I'm gonna tweet it out right now we
have any public API at API kamidana hey
I and you guys can go there and you guys
can check it out so is that
yeah yeah let's do that
[Music]
yeah and that's important for you can
use it today everything on there is
available in production and used by
comma Connect Explorer Cabana and
hopefully the tools that y'all are gonna
write with this you know this has been a
you know we're highly requested desire
feature for quite a while
release so yeah I'll post that tweet and
Twitter of the Queen in discord
yeah so all the data that you upload to
us is uploaded through this API and then
redownload through this API we make
things available to you well you can
like just interact with your devices you
can download all the raw files you can
see things about routes you can see your
device location through Athena yeah
Athena Athena is the service that runs
on your ego on and then this API if you
go down to Athena lets you actually
interact with your device live on the
network so our server exit proxy server
it's the server goes back down to the
bus that's over
yeah that's very nice - exactly like
Newman on this monitor so they can move
the tripod I'm gonna move the tripod oh
they couldn't even like see what I was
doing the computer I know I would like
to get a tripod with wheels you know
yeah yeah so next you guys know all your
eons have dongle IDs and the segment is
one minute of driving and then a route
is a bunch of segments we use JWT use to
authenticate you go over here to JW t
comma Dada Y you can grab yourself a JWT
not gonna do that in front of you
someone someone will type it all in
somebody would go to all the trouble you
think to type in the date I'm gonna be
truncated actually does hmm you can get
the first so many digits characters yeah
yeah but um yeah the way so you can just
go right in here to the Combinator VT
portal it's like a quick login yeah you
login with your Google account
yeah you can paste it in on the API
Doc's here and then all of the example
requests on the right column you can
paste right into your terminal and try
it out with your data nice you can get
stuff about user stuff about your device
all your routes the data live will not
live video streams video streams iceborn
Cabana use that derive data we're
talking about stuff about vehicles how
open pilot talks ena which is the
service of talk to all the pilot all
your annotations that use an explorer
and one global leader boy yeah it's
actually just the top 40 oh but like you
used to see in the community page so
yeah highly encouraged cost them
leaderboard customer we're at 153 where
have you been man
yeah I have a definition section Oh does
that mean you can build your own
Explorer well you could do one better
than that and you mean one better than
that and use our Explorer five is gonna
make - the thing but we're gonna make
the Explorer Explorer is open source oh
[Music]
yeah I'm gonna hide the you're right
you're right I'm just gonna look at you
and II oh you'll see them in the API
Doc's yeah common points if you guys
remember what explorers really
appreciate all the annotations that have
been provided whenever you disengage or
nauseous steering wheel a bit and you go
on Explorer and commit an annotation
especially all the comments we've
received associated with the annotations
are incredibly useful so we go back and
improve the driving system based on your
feedback yeah but now explores open
source really you know once you see
issues created want to see issues
resolved pull requests are accepted you
know comments really been you know
accepting a lot of pull requests lately
and comments team and our open source
ecosystem is as healthy and active as
ever so you know we're trying to get
everything out there so that so that we
can build calm a on alright
no but then other people said it was
fine but you know what we're gonna get a
proper mic audio you can get that from
your eyes hold a boom we're gonna get a
boom that you just like plug in one more
thing so Explorer is the tool who are
annotating the drives and reviewing the
drives cabaña is the tool for exploring
the can data on your car we have this
great project called open BBC which has
been in the works for yeah we came up
with it spring 2017 so all the cars have
they don't have public eight guys the
car is the way our modules communicate
with each other is all secret the
manufacturers have this documentation
file called the DBC
but you know you can try asking them for
I don't think that's gonna go over that
well or you can reverse engineer it and
in open DBC here we have really all
mainstream cars now reverse engineer by
people and they're pretty complete and
it allows you to get things like your
your wheel speeds you can get your
steering angle sensor right here but we
used to have this thing called Cabana
issues where you could publish your
issues about Cabana Cabana have bugs
we're doing we're doing one better than
that now we're not just gonna you know
look at look we can hire a full-time
person to fix all the Cabana issues that
cost money and we're company we're
trying to make money so we're gonna do
one bed we're gonna open source it so
you guys can fix the issues yourself
right here at the comic
Wow is it it's really that easy huh also
explore and oh we should put licenses on
them that's a good bow these
applications are based on react and we
are using the latest , API and DM
package which is also under comma API on
our github which implements the I
suspect that we showed you earlier so I
hope that everyone plays around with
these and customizes them in the ways
they want and the ways that we all deem
fit to merge back in will merge in make
it good yeah someone's asking how does
anyone start contributing to the
codebase is there any tutorial on
walkthrough of the codebase yes I write
the instructions to get started on the
project there in readme at the root of
each repo and you know since they're
written in JavaScript can react very
cross-platform you know pretty pretty
easy to get familiar with it should be
easy to get up and running and make
simple changes and see them reflected in
front of you that's the beauty of the
web you can just make a change and the
tools are so good that it'll
automatically reload in front of you and
show you what you did so yeah read names
arcs yeah so was asking to post that
link and we
maybe just perfect this guy yeah yeah
cabanas 2017 brainchild we were all
sitting downstairs in the basement of
the old office and we were like how
are we gonna afford all these cars we
came up with open D BC and we came up
with Cabana just some one one random
evening so you know ideas blossom and
open DBC is a incredibly successful
project and we wouldn't have been able
to do it without all of you it's not
done yet every time new car comes out
and all the cars that haven't been have
the map yet we still need your help so
hop on cabana get an e on and help
reverse an engineer every car that we
can cuz a Kyle boat was on legs creep
and you guys can watch the watched the
podcast and you know cruisers virtually
making an aftermarket self-driving kit
but they gave up not because there
wasn't a market but because it's
technically with a guard how are you
going to support Carl I believe said
twenty to fifty cars well support
[Music]
11:12 well I'm only up to Honda 13 14 15
16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 36 37
38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 and if
you include the model years we probably
got like 65 right there so and that's
dude tools like Cabana I'm making it
possible to crowdsource this kind of
work
we don't own 45 different cars this is a
similar idea right how are we going to
get rid of the long tail of issues so
always remember open pilot and every
other driving system today is level 2
which means it works in conjunction with
a human not alone pay attention at all
times and correct its mistakes now its
mistakes you're usually you can do these
things Explorer was this to kind of show
you what the car was thinking at the
time we draw the models we draw where
the car was going and we've already
open-source least amount of the tools
that we use and explore so the libraries
we use to draw the HUD and read the logs
are already open source under common AI
organization I'm p.m. so we have common
a I log reader to read logs in in
JavaScript coming we have our old
JavaScript engineer shadows Chris bakery
Road Cathy NP JavaScript tooling so you
can read all your log on us you can even
check them out yeah you just think about
how bad all the other throughout the
people modded cars well you the tools
are terrible like we try to ball I don't
want to build anything I never want to
build anything right if I can download
something I'd much rather gallery you
think I wanted to build pandas by
shopping
yeah we built Cabana kiss you know you
got back your tools which are
proprietary for Windows and cost
thousands of dollars and we thought
there's no reason that good free tools
shouldn't exist now now cabanas pretty
truly free MIT license and an
open-source
cross you know compatible across
platform doesn't require 200 mega
Windows download you gotta know oh I
need these I need visual C components
redistributable 2015 oh now you just
need Chrome yeah yeah stream is choppy
it's choppy you don't think we should be
on Wi-Fi well I know because I'm on why
fine fine cool yeah check out everything
was released today submit issues give
feedback on discord and Twitter and
everything and you were excited to see
what you build yeah we'll take
reasonable questions no product
announcement guys it's for developers
remember
oh yeah bring back the old office I love
comma but work out how to appeal to the
normal drivers
that's what's what's happening in the
announcements that aren't for developers
as announced this announcements for
develop July 1st through the masses yeah
definitely good analysis track to the
masses row we have a new slogan about
our new slogan oh yeah check out her
Twitter check out our Twitter you know
how it used to be go sure I get rid of
the hashtag anti-hype I think we should
just like make driving chills simple
enough you don't need to make driving
chill period right that's our that's our
new slogan mix ride and chill it's like
ghost riding for the masses but it's
make driving yeah
how many retweets what about the dataset
though ya know soon your date actually
what about the Dennison you know what
what about the day is that why don't you
go to comment search for comics who k-19
what about the dataset I'm just gonna
link you back here on Twitter what about
the data already published bro we open
source data at the end of last year how
do you plan on growing your data set
it's already too big guys it's too much
alright maybe we should take them yeah
we have 119 over a 200 we'll do that but
yeah I know
oh let's talk about the eons without the
extra costume scoffs bro I'm not making
any money off of your costumes why
should I pay for cuz you made poor
choices I said we live in a democracy
I assume you made poor choices when you
voted about Netflix on yon no yeah we
have a lot of data data is really
expensive to store you know so who's our
largest yeah yes which is going down
well we're bringing all the data right
here to San Diego mm-hmm yeah it's like
retirement 30 data common navigation no
host stream start kar komak connect it
seems to be a gimmicky feature that
people want and the only business car
bug is early in there oh wow this stream
is lagging it's terrible you still have
a country
0.6 when we don't make comments on
future products and ETA navigate an open
pilot I'll say this anyone who wants
navigate on copilot should read the
Consumer Reports review of navigator on
autopilot now soon reports for anyone's
company no not there not there not
bought out and all sold out at least as
far as I can tell and they're very Pro
autopilot but navigating autopilot is
not good when it makes lane changes it
doesn't worse than human right
you should we only try to do things
where no driving miserable Lane it's
pretty easy to do better than a human
people's aren't that good even if you're
not like super distracting sometime like
the wheel drift a little and jerk it
back right control loops are much faster
and when you're making a lane change
there's so much human intuition that
goes into it that unless you can
actually do it in a better than human
way you shouldn't be doing it at all and
that seems to be like most of what
navigate on autopilot is now combined
with navigation in like intelligent
place this is something we're interested
in the future of a building something
that looks like navigating an autopilot
and works like navigate on I got an
original bottle three boats great very
little pop I tried out navigate
I wouldn't shut that I think it's I
think it's a alpha you hear low Danica's
people definitely don't like it someone
say in statistics show that auto steer
is what people really use this is a
great article Kristen Carosa great
journalist oh the one that breaks 200
this one oh I think we're talking about
the one that breaks down like which
features people want you know yeah
what's the latest development on the
Corolla it drives
okay maybe I should carry tweets move up
retweets people buy things by the way
please buy things shop up da da da di we
love when you buy things
that's exactly right it makes it very
easy to buy what we should call it the
role or not the Corolla yes someone just
caught that that's brilliant patron why
am i buying you a trip to Europe bro
because someone in community bought
chase and a few others - why yeah camera
will man thank you I am a woman I know
that's true someone wants to know the
best car for 0.6 parole law yeah Corolla
check out Longo Cleo - yeah give a shout
out to the guy who helped you yeah I
think it's Steven it longer do you just
hear any new announcements so what we
announced today is that we now have an
API I will post a public API it is right
there
we've also open sourced Explorer and
the tools that you've been using for the
last three years let's have a call to
action wrap-up those are good to have oh
yeah yes you can go and comment a I
Cabana issues and we're gonna turn this
off and you could port the issues over
to combat AI Cabana we already have
issue though these might be internal
vegetables oh yeah remove the stupid
three minutes go by yeah all right yeah
cool